hey guys this looks like a fun one this
is another Katrina a puzzle and it's day
two of our Advent calendar we're going
to solve 31 Catrina a puzzles in the
month of December one for each day and
this is December 2nd it tells us that we
have three squares and that the smallest
has an area of seven and it wants to
know what's the total shaded area if you
want to try it on your own pause it
right now cuz I'm going to solve it in 3
2 1 first let's label the sides of the
larger Square X and let's label the
sides of this smaller Square y we can
now write a formula for the Shaded area
the Shaded area will be equal to the
large Square which is X2 minus this
Square which is y^ 2 minus this Square
which is 7 this is what we're trying to
solve for let's put a box around it so
to move forward I'm going to make one
assumption that isn't explicitly stated
and that is that this semi circle is
intersecting this square at these
Corners I don't know how I would solve
it without that assumption so I'm going
to make that assumption comment if you
have another way to solve it that
doesn't use that assumption using that
assumption I'm going to draw the line
from here to here this is the radius of
this semicircle the semicircle has a
diameter of X which means the radius
would be half of that or X over 2 and
then next let's draw this perpendicular
line this is the same length as the side
of this square and this square has an
area of 7 so the side length is square <
TK of 7 which means this has a length of
square < TK of 7 and last let's connect
this right here this distance is half
the side of this Square so it's going to
be y/ 2 now let's play around with this
right triangle as usual we're going to
use the Pythagorean theorem which is A2
+ B2 = c^2 in the place of the a we'll
plug in this side right here < TK 7 in
the place of the B we'll plug in this
side which is y over 2 and in the place
of the C we'll plug in this side which
is X
over2 for the first term the square root
and the square will cancel each other
out so we're left with seven for the
next term the exponent distributes to
both the top and the bottom giving us
y^2 over 2^2 and same thing over here
this changes into x^2 over 2^2 and then
let's simplify this 2^2 is equal to 4
2^2 is equal to 4 and let's give this 7
a common denominator 7 is going to be
the same thing as 284 and now that these
have the same denominator we can write
them as a single fraction 28 + y^2 over
4 next I don't really like fractions so
let's get rid of this denominator we can
multiply both sides of the equation by
four this four and this four will cancel
each other out and this four and this
four will cancel each other out so now
we have 28 + y^2 is equal to x^2 let's
subtract y^2 from both sides on the left
hand side these y^2 will cancel each
other out so we'll have 28 and that'll
be equal to x^2 - y^2 which is x^2 - y^2
and check this out we needed x^2 - y^2
in the place of this x^2 - y^2 we can
plug in 28 28 28 - 7 is equal to 21 and
there's no units in the original problem
so we'll give it a label of units
squared this is the answer to our
question it's already in a box how
exciting this was day two of our agvent
calendar this will be day three this is
the video that we'll be doing tomorrow
we want to know what is the area of this
shaded region divided by the area of the
entire circle how exciting